자   이번에   게임은웰컴   투   코룬   구룡에   오신   것을
Now This time Welcome to the game Too Kolun Kowloon Coming to
Now, this time the game is Welcome to Korun Kowloon
환영합니다라는   스팀   신작   공포게임이고요   게임   가격은
Welcome Steam new horror game game price
It's a new horror game on Steam called Welcome. The price of the game is
7,800원입니다토끼님의   한글패치를   받아   진행하게
7,800 won. Rabbit's   Hangul patch   receive   to proceed
It is 7,800 won. I will proceed with the rabbit's Korean patch.
됐습니다이   게임의   스토리는   당신은저렴한   주거지를   찾기   위해   구룡이라는
The   story of this   game is   you find   an affordable   house
The story of this game is that you go to Kowloon to find cheap housing.
지역의   오게   됐습니다   이곳에   주민들은얼핏   보기에   평범한   사람들처럼
The   of the region  has come  The residents of this place   look like   ordinary   people at first glance.
The residents here look like normal people at first glance.
보이지만   더   깊이   파고들면   그들의진짜   모습을   보게   될   것입니다라고
If you look  more  and dig deeper  , you will   see their real
But if you dig deeper, you will see their true face.
하네요   그럼   바로   한번   해보도록하겠습니다
Then Immediately I'll try it once
Well then, I'll try it right away
구룡   성벽도시   199년
Kowloon Fortress City 199 years
Kowloon Walled City 199 years
안개가   자욱한   중국   칸을   아래에는인구가   가장   많은   도시이자   가난과
Foggy fog China Khan below is the  most  city with the most population and poverty and
Beneath the foggy Chinese city of Cannes is the most populous city, poverty and
갱단의   폭력이   만연한   도시인   구룡이자리하고   있습니다
Gangsters violence plenty cityin Kowloon is located
It is home to Kowloon, a city with rampant gang violence.
[음악]
[music]
그러나   아직   젊은   학생의   경우   저렴한방을   구하는   것이   가장   우선적이고
However,   for   still   young   students,   finding an inexpensive room  is   the most  priority.
However, for young students, finding a cheap room is the first priority.
시급한   일이죠
It's urgent
It's urgent.
근데실제로   있는   장소인가   봐
But is it actually a   place   look
But I guess it's a real place
분위기   좋다
atmosphere   good
good mood
도시에   벽   안에서는   무엇이   그를기다리고   있을까요
In the city wall  what is   waiting for him
What awaits him within the walls of the city
자   지금   건물   안에들어왔습니다   상당히   퀄리티가   좋죠
Now   now   the building   came in   quite   the quality is   good
Now, I'm in the building. The quality is quite good.
엄청   잘   만들었는데
I made it very   well
I made it very well
한번   가보자
let's go
내   집이   어디지   근데
My   home  where is   but
where is my house
뭔가   사람들   소리   들린다
I can hear something people sounds
I hear some people
무슨   파티   중인가
What   party  are you doing?
what party are you having
퀄리티   진짜   좋은데
Quality Really It's good
The quality is really good
[음악]여기가   내   집인가
[Music] Is this   my   home?
[Music] Is this my home
여기   아닌   거   같네요
It's like   not   here
I don't think it's here
아무것도   없나
nothing
is there anything
응   왠지   여기   같기도   하고여기도   아닌가   보네
Yeah Somehow Here It looks like   and here too   Isn't it   I see
Yeah, somehow it seems like here, but it doesn't seem to be here either.
어디서   노래   소리가   흘러나온다
Where does the   song  sound   come from?
where does the sound of the song come from
잠겼는데열쇠   같은게   필요한가
It's locked, but I need a key
It's locked, do you need a key or something?
여긴가   어   열린다
Is this place   uh   open
Is this place open?
딱   귀신   나올   것   같아
Just like a   ghost  will come out
It looks like a ghost will come out
이런   데는   집값이   얼마길래
how much is the house price
What is the price of a house here
난   몇   만원   하나4층   하필   4층이야
I'm   how many   10,000 won   one 4th floor   all the way   4th floor
I'm on the 4th floor for tens of thousands of won.
뭔가   불길하네요
Something   is on fire
Something's on fire
여기   층수   뭐   안내가   안   돼   있는
Here   number of floors  what  guide not  available
There is no information about the number of floors here
뭔가   근데   분위기가잠깐만   이런데   막   들어가도   되는   거야
Something   but   the atmosphere is like this for a moment   it's like this   just go in
Something, but the atmosphere is like this for a moment. You can just go in.
작은   골반   같아   보이는
It looks like a small pelvis
looks like a small pelvis
분위기가   으스스해
The atmosphere is   spooky
the atmosphere is eerie
다음번   둘러봐야겠다
Next time   I'll have to look around
I'll have to look around next time
여기   상처도   막혀   있고요
There are also   wounds   blocked
The wound is blocked here too
어디   개   키우나   봐
Where   dogs   grow   look
look where the dog is
아   왠지   귀신   나올   것   같아뭔   소리야
Ah   somehow   it seems like a ghost   will come out   what   is that sound
Oh, it seems like a ghost will come out. What are you talking about?
초인종   소리   뭐지
Doorbell Sound What is it?
what's the doorbell sound
강아지는여기서   뭐   하니
The dog is here   what
What is the puppy doing here
응걔가   불쌍해   배고파   보여
Yeah, he's   pitiful   hungry   I can see
I feel sorry for him. He looks hungry.
먹을게   없구나
I have nothing to eat
there's nothing to eat
어둡네요잠겼어
It's dark. It's locked.
여긴   뭐야
What is
what is this
이렇게   뭐임냄새가   심해
Like this   what it smells like   it's so bad
It smells so bad
여기   쓰레기   버리는   곳이야
This is the  garbage dumping  place
this is the garbage dump
문이   있는데   이렇게   쓰레기가
There is a door , but   like this   trash
There's a door, but there's garbage like this
잘   지내   나중에형이   먹을   거   사다   줄게
Well   get by   later hyung  I'll buy you   something   to eat   I'll give it to you
Take care, I'll buy you something to eat later
[음악]
[music]
왜   이렇게   어두운   거야
Why   is this   dark
why is it so dark
여기   갈   수   있나
can you go  here
can i go here
여기   전력   그런곳인가   보다   마치
Here   electric power   is that a place  than   just like
It seems like this is a place like power
괜찮네요
it's okay
여기는   왜   이렇게   막아놨지못   들어가게
This is   why  like this   I couldn't block it   let me in
Why is this place blocked like this so I can't enter?
어위로   올라가는
Going up
going up
길이   막혔는데
The road   is blocked
The road is blocked
벌레   소리
bug sound
bug sounds
어떻게   하지
What do we do
여긴가여기다
this is it
이거   열면   바로   또   집이   아니라   또복도   형식이다
This open right again home not tto-hallway it's hyung
As soon as you open this, it's not a house again, it's a hallway again
그렇지
yes
뭔   소리야
What   is that
what are you talking about
잘못   들었나
did you hear wrong
누구   우는데
who   is crying
who is crying
누구세요
who are you
울음소리가   사라졌어
The cries   are gone
the cries are gone
여긴가   나갔다   오마   열쇠는   가게에맡겨뒀어   입구   밖에   있을   거야
Is this place  out   Oma  I left the key   at the store  there will be   outside the entrance
Is this place gone? Oh, I left the key at the store. It will be outside the entrance.
무슨   소리야힘들게   올라왔더니   어
What   is that so hard   I came up   uh
What are you talking about?
입고   밖에이   입구   얘기하는   거   아니겠지   설마
Dressed  outside entrance talking wasn't it  no way
I'm not talking about this entrance outside wearing it, no way
건물   입고   얘기하는   건가   가게에맡겨   뒀어   밖에   있을   거야
The building wearing talking is it  leaving it to the store I put it outside it will be
Are you wearing a building and talking? I left it to the store.
왠지   돌아가는동안에
Somehow   while going back
while going back
또   소리   들었지   오는   소리
I heard the   sound  again   the coming   sound
I heard a sound again
일단   내려가자
Let's go down
let's go down
어   왜   기운   차렸어   갑자기   어너   배고파서   또
Uh Why Cheer up Suddenly Ahner Because I'm hungry  Again
Hey, why did you get your energy back?
난   아니야   어
I'm   no   uh
I'm not
맞지
Right
그런   생각하면   안   돼
If you think   like that,   no  you can
don't think like that
뭐야방금   봤어
what is it i just saw
what did you just see
여기   아까
here
here earlier
뭔가   있었는데
there was something
[음악]
[music]
아니   아까   여기   이렇게   사람이   이렇게팔   내밀고   있다가   이렇게   싹   사라짐
No  before here like this someone extended like this and stayed there like this sprout disappeared
No, just now, a person was extending his arms like this and then he disappeared like this.
이게   뭔가요
what is this
너   나가자
you   let's go
let's go out
나왔습니다
came out
아까보다는   좀   더시끄러운   거   같기도   하고
Compared to before
It seems to be a bit noisier than before.
계세요[음악]
Stay [Music]
집주인을   쓴   글에   적힌   가게인   거같아
It looks like   the owner of the house  and   the shopkeeper
It seems to be the store written in the landlord's writing
열쇠가   여기   어딘가   있을   텐데   어   개사료
The key is  here somewhere  it must be  uh dog food
The key must be here somewhere, uh dog food
어   사료   챙길   수   있다   어   내가   줄수   있나   봐
Uh Food I can take care of it I can I can I I can give it to you I can  Look
Uh, I can take care of the food, I guess I can give it to you
근데   이렇게   훔쳐가도   되는   거야열쇠를   한번   찾아봅시다
But   like this   even if you steal it   it'll work   Let's find the key  once
But you can steal it like this. Let's find the key.
[음악]
[music]
아   이거   디테일   괜찮다   게임   어이거다   열쇠
Ah This Detail It's okay Game Hey it's  Key
Ah, this detail is ok, it's a game, it's a key
챙겼어
I got it
나가자
Let's go out
이대로   나가도   되겠지
I can go out like this
[음악]
[music]
뭐야   아   깜짝   놀랐네아니   갑자기   노래가
What is it  Ah Surprised I was surprised No Suddenly The song
What is it, I was surprised. No, suddenly the song
끊기면서   노이즈   소리   들렸는데너무   몰입하고   있었나   어   삼치   됐다
As it cut off  Noise Sound I heard it, but it was so I was immersed was it  uh Samchi
I heard noise as it cut off, but I was too immersed.
방금뭐야
what did you just do
자   다시   들어왔습니다열쇠도   챙겼고   우리
Now  I came in again  I also got the key  and   we
Well, I came back. I took the key and we
강아지한테   줄   사료도   챙겼어아   진짜   하지   마   아
I got   food for the dog  too   I really did  I don't do it   don't   ah
I also packed some food for the puppy. Really, don’t do that.
깜짝   놀랐네이거   뭐야
Surprised   I was surprised   what is it
I'm surprised what is this
뭔데
What
아건물이   노후돼서
The building is   old
Because the building is old
방금   또벨소리   초인종
Just   Another ringing   Doorbell
The doorbell just rang
기다렸지
waited
자
ruler
아니   먹어[음악]
no   eat [music]
no eat [music]
혹시   몰라   한   번   더   둘러보자
Maybe   don't know  once  once  more  let's look around
In case you don't know, let's look around one more time
이런   장소가   원래
This   place is   originally
this place was originally
어   있던가   내가   이렇게   문을   열   수가있었나
How   was it   was I   able to   open the door   like this
How could I have opened the door like this?
아까   못   봤었나   아직
Did you   not   see it before   yet
Haven't you seen it before?
여기   들어가도   되나
can I go in here
can i come in here
아   가지   말까
Ah   should I go   or not?
Oh, shouldn't I go
뭔가   가까이   가니까   소리가   잘   봐
Something  is getting closer  so   the sound  look well
I'm getting close to something, so I can hear the sound
뭔가   처음   넘어가는   거   마냥근데
Something   for the first time   it's like passing
It's like going over something for the first time
사람들   소리가   들리잖아아무렇지도   않겠지
You can hear people sounds , nothing will happen
You can hear people, it's nothing
[음악]어떻게   하지
[Music] How to
[MUSIC] How do I do it
한번호기심
Curiosity
[음악]아니다   아니   아니야   아니야   아니야
[Music] No No No No No
[Music] no no no no no
아니야   아니야   이건   아닌   거   같아아닌   거   같아
No No This is  Not  It’s like  It’s not  It’s like
no no i don't think this is not i don't think it is
뭐야아니   애초에   올라가는   길이   막혔네   어
What is it no   in the first place   the way up   was blocked
What is it? No, the way up was blocked in the first place.
아까   이러지   않았는데아   그래서   여기로   가야   된다는   거구나
I didn't do this   earlier   but   so   I have to go   here   it's saying
I didn't do this before, but that's why I have to go here.
분위기가[음악]
atmosphere [music]
[음악]
[music]
자   잘   나왔어요   지금   여기   우리집인가
Now  well I came out now here is this my house?
Well, it came out well. Is this my house now?
집   그쪽이지라인
Home there Easyline
that side of the house
아닌가[음악]
Isn't it [music]
맞네잘   나온   거   맞아
That's right   came out   that's   that's right
That's right, that's right
[음악]
[music]
아까   못   들어갔던   문이   열리는   거고여기로   가면   돼
I couldn't go in earlier   The door  will open  and go here   and you can
The door you couldn't enter earlier will open. You can go here.
[음악]자   집에   왔습니다
[Music] Now I'm home
[MUSIC] Now I'm home
[음악]
[music]
집이   많이   어두운데어떻게
The house is   very   dark, how can you
The house is very dark
화장실
restroom
야   변기   이거   위에   있는   거   봐봐
Hey Toilet Look at this  on the   thing
Hey, look at what's on the toilet
좋네뷰   좋네
nice view   nice
nice view nice
여기는창고네요   창고
This is a warehouse   warehouse
This is a warehouse. A warehouse.
어   생각보다   근데   여기   나   혼자지내는   데가   맞나   아닌가   사람들이랑
Uh It's more than I thought But Here Me I'm living alone Destination Is that right Isn't it With people
Uh, it's better than I thought, but is it right for me to be alone here with people?
같이   쓰는
write   together
write together
아   집주인의   방   공동   그런   건가   보다맞지
Ah Landlord's  room joint That's  That's more correct than
Ah, the landlord's room is more like that, right?
여기가   이제내   집일   수도   있고요
This is   Now my   I work at home   I can do it
This could be my home now
다른데   먼저   한번   가볼까
It's different   first   once   should I go?
Shall we go somewhere else first?
여기   주방이네
This is the   kitchen
here is the kitchen
[음악]엄청   노후됐다   진짜
[Music] Very   old   really
[Music] Very old, really
시설이발코니   문이   닫혀   있대
Facility Balcony Door Closed They say
The facility says the balcony door is closed
이   나방들   뭐야   도대체어
These   moths   what the hell   what the heck
What the hell are these moths
이곳이   내   방이야
This is   my   room
this is my room
먼저   침대   위에   짐을   올려놓자
First, let's put the   luggage  on the   bed
Let's put the luggage on the bed first
일단   문   닫자따뜻한   차   한잔을   마시고   싶어
Let's close the door I want to drink a cup of warm tea
Let's close the door for now, I want to drink a cup of warm tea
이거   왜   안   열려어
This   why  not   open
why isn't this open
침대   때문에   안   열리는   건가
Because of the bed  Not Is it open
Doesn't it open because of the bed?
막힌   거   같은데
I think it's blocked
I think I'm stuck
일단   차   한잔   마시고   오자
Let's go   for a cup of tea  and have a drink
Let's have a cup of tea and come
여기   가서
go here
기다리면   되겠죠
If you wait   it will work
You can wait
이제   먹게   해줄게얼마나   먹고   싶었으면   두   번   얘기하네
Now   eat   how much   eat  if you want   two   times   talk
I'll let you eat now. If you want to eat, tell me twice.
[음악]
[music]
방금   뭔가   소리
I just heard   something
just heard something
뭔가   들렸는데
I heard something
원샷   했어
One shot   I did
one shot
내   방으로   가자너   이렇게   소리가
Let's go to my room You  like this
Let's go to my room.
어   여기   원래   이렇게   열렸던가
Uh here originally was it open like this
Uh, did it originally open like this?
이제   열리네
Now   is open
now open
뭐야나   무서워   집에   가고   싶은데   집주인
What is it?
I'm scared of something, I want to go home, but the landlord
할머니가   미친   거   같아   오랫동안   밖에나가지   못하고   있단   말이야
My grandma is  crazy   for a long time and she  hasn't been able to
I think grandma is crazy. She hasn't been out for a long time.
[음악]
[music]
여기   무슨   소리야
What   is this
what are you talking about here
말도   안   돼   하지만   만일을   대비해현관문을   확인하는   것이   좋겠어
No It's okay But Just in case It's better  to check the front door
No way, but you better check the front door just in case
[음악]어떻게   확인해
[Music] How to check
[MUSIC] How to check
[음악]
[music]
뭐야
what
여기   참을수
I can't stand it
can't stand it here
야   진짜   못   나가게   막혔는데길이
Hey   I really can't   I can't get out   I'm blocked
Hey, I really couldn't go out, but the road was blocked.
[음악]어떻게
[Music] How
[음악]걸어   잠궜어
[Music] Walk it   I locked it
[Music] Locked up
나   여기   이제   같이   건가[음악]
Me here  now  is it like   [Music]
Am I here with you now [Music]
어떻게   하지
What do we do
망했다   잘못   걸렸다
It's ruined Wrong Caught
ruined got it wrong
[음악]
[music]
방금   본   사람[음악]
The  person I just saw [Music]
The One You Just Saw [Music]
쉿
Shh
할머니가   나   쳐다보고   있었어원래
Grandmother I  was looking  Originally
Grandma was looking at me
[음악]저기요
[Music] Hey
[음악]
[music]
밤에   함부로   밖에   나가지   말려
At night   recklessly   go out   stop
Don't go out recklessly at night
저기요   지금출구를   찾아봐야겠어   아니   뭐야   할머니
Hey  I need to find an exit  No What is it Grandma
Hey, I need to find an exit right now, no, what is it, grandma?
[음악]어떻게   하지
[Music] How to
[MUSIC] How do I do it
[음악]
[music]
왜   이래   이거사방이   뭔가   이상해   지금
Why   is this   this is everywhere   something   strange   right now
Why is this happening? Something is strange everywhere right now
왜   스스로   물을[음악]
Why   ask yourself   [Music]
Ask yourself why [music]
이렇게   문   열렸고   지금   잠깐만화장실에서   소리   들린다
Like this  door opened now I can hear   from the comic room for a while
The door opened like this, and now I can hear a sound from the comic room.
[음악]
[music]
계세요
anybody home
지금   샤워하러   들어갔나   할머니[음악]
Now I went to take a shower  Grandma [Music]
Did you go to the shower now grandma [music]
지금이야   빨리   뭔가   찾아봐야   돼
It's now quickly something you have to find it
Now is the time to find something
알고   큰일났다   이거여기   미쳤어
I know It's a big problem This is here It's crazy
It was a big deal knowing this is crazy here
빨리   나가야   돼[음악]
Hurry up   I have to get out   I can [Music]
Gotta get out soon [Music]
어떻게   하지[음악]
How to   [Music]
how do i do it [music]
마음의   준비놀라지   않아
Heart of  preparation I'm not surprised
Prepare your mind, don't be surprised
[음악]
[music]
천천히천천히
slowly slowly
[음악]
[music]
어떻게   하지[음악]
How to   [Music]
how do i do it [music]
어떻게
how
하지[음악]
not [music]
[음악]어떻게   하지
[Music] How to
[MUSIC] How do I do it
못하지[음악]
can't [music]
잠깐만
wait for a sec
[음악]어떡해
[Music] What can I do?
큰일   났어
A big deal   happened
big trouble
[음악]
[music]
뭐야   나   잡힌   건가설마   갇힌   거   아니지
What is  I caught I can't believe it I'm trapped it's not
What is it that I got caught?
아이고아이고
Oh my, oh my
큰일났다
it's a big deal
뭐야
what
왜   문이   이거밖에   안   열리지
Why does the   door  only open   this one?
Why does the door only open this way
이거   쳐다보라는   거잖아
This   is what you mean by looking
You want me to look at this
아   진짜
Oh really
어떻게   이거
how   this
how is this
손전등   같은   거   없나   너무   어둡잖아
Is there any  like a flashlight  It's too dark
Is there such a thing as a flashlight? It's too dark
일단   주변을   좀   조사
First of all,   the surroundings   a little   research
Do some research around
헉   열린다   그   열쇠가   여기   건가   봐아까   얻었던   거
Heck It's open That Is the key here  Look earlier I got it
Heck, it's open. I think the key is here. I got it earlier.
다   왔어
Everything   is here
I'm here
어   여기   어디야
uh here where are you
uh where are you
요즘   마을   상황이   이상하다   마치   내가위험에   처한   거   같다   보수공사가
These days The situation  is strange It's like I'm in danger It's like  Repair works
The situation in the village is strange these days. It seems like I am in danger.
끝나면   빨리   이사를   가야겠다
When it's over  I'm going to move   quickly
I'm going to move soon after I'm done
누구야
who is this
아   왜요
ah  why
Oh why
무슨   소리지
what   are you talking about
what are you talking about
계세요
anybody home
뭐야
what
뭔데
What
뭔데   도대체
what the hell
냉장고   문   왜   자꾸   열렸다   닫혔다는거야
Refrigerator Door Why Keep  open It's closed
Why does the refrigerator door keep opening and closing?
어두워서   안   보이잖아
It's dark   I can't see it
I can't see you because it's dark
여기   이제   들어갈
here   now   go in
now go in here
수   있다   열쇠   열쇠
can  have key key
can key key
아   뒤돌기가   너무   싫다
Ah   I hate turning around   so much
Oh, I hate turning back
방금   봤지
I just saw
just saw
카톡   튀는   아니었어   누가   다   쳐다보게했거든
KakaoTalk It wasn't bouncing  Who  made everyone look at it
It wasn't KakaoTalk that stood out because someone made everyone stare
근데   열쇠   어디   열쇠지
But   the key  where is the   key
But where is the key
여기겠지
I guess it's here
자물쇠인데비밀번호   형식인   것   같아
It's a lock, but it's the same as the password type
It's a lock, but I think it's in the form of a password
이거마침
this is over
지금   우리
now we
모르죠
I don't know
다른   데서   뭐   알아야   되나
In another   place  What  I need to know
What else should I know
[음악]
[music]
카톡도   조심일단부터
Kakao Talk  Be careful
Be careful with KakaoTalk from the beginning
아   깜짝아
Ah   surprise
Oh surprise
가운데   씨가운데   C   같지   시
Middle Cmiddle C  Same as City
Middle C, like C in the middle
이거   뒤에   돌려보면은   가운데   씨야나머지도   어디
After this  , if you look back   in the middle,   and the rest of   where
If you turn this around, where is the middle of the field?
산소가   있을   거야
There will be   oxygen
there will be oxygen
아   이것도
Ah  this too
Oh this too
아까   왔던데요
I came earlier
I just came
별거   없
nothing
no big deal
네   아   그림들이   단선가땡이씨
Yes Ah Pictures Danseon Gattaengi
Yes, the pictures are single line
땡이씨땡   이씨
Lee
Mr. Ddaeng Lee Ddaeng Lee
뺑이씨그림들   찾아야   돼
Hit-and-run pictures   I have to find them   I can
I need to find the paintings of Mr.
아
ah
땡이   CA땡   e   c   a
Ddaeng CA Ddaeng e c a
Ding CA Ding eca
땡   이씨   a   yecay   그럼   첫   번째   거만   찾으면
Ttaeng   Mr. Lee a yecay  Then   first   second   arrogant
If you find the first one
돼잘   기억해   주세요
It's okay   remember   please
please remember
오케이   마지막   하나
Okay   the last   one
ok last one
여기   하나   있으려나
Would you like to be here   Hana
want to have one here
가림   하나   어디   있을까
Garim Hana Where  is it?
Where is the cover
소리
sound
가   아니   근데   마지막   그림도   찾아야진행이   되지   않을까
Go   no   but   I have to find the last   drawing   to make progress   wouldn't it be
No, but I need to find the last picture.
근데   여기   안에서는   내가그림을
But   here   inside   I draw
But in here, I'm painting
얘는   아까   자물쇠에   클릭이   안   됐단말이야
This guy   just now   clicked   on the lock  it didn't work
He said the lock didn't click earlier.
단서   다   모아야만
Clues   all   must be gathered
Gather all the clues
진행이   될   수   있어서
Because progress can be
can proceed
화장실   바닥에
bathroom on the floor
on the bathroom floor
있을   수도   있잖아
maybe there is
there might be
이거다   이거
this is   this
this is this
대체   자   d
Substitute  ja d
substitute d
자   풀자
Now   let's solve
let's solve
a   y
Oh
나갔습니다   이제나갈   수   있는   건가
I'm out   I'm leaving now   I can   is there
I left, can I leave now?
혹   바로바로
Or   right away
Or right
따로   있어
Separate
stay apart
아이   코너   왜   이렇게   무섭지
Ai corner why  is this   scary
Why is the child's corner so scary?
자   여기만   열면   돼
Now   just open it here
Now, just open it here
나왔어
I'm here
드디어드디어   나왔어
Finally, finally   came out
finally it finally came out
이제   나갈   수   있나
Now   can you go out
can i go now
나가야   돼
I have to go   okay
I have to go out
가야   돼
go   yes
I have to go
빨리   도망가야   돼
Hurry up   run away   okay
I have to run away quickly
빨리
hurry
아까   그   강아지   어디   갔어   은혜   갚아나한테   이거   아니지
Earlier   that   puppy   where   went   Grace   pay me back   this   it's not
Where did that puppy go earlier?
나   위기의   상황도   도와주려   강아지가살아도   줬는데   그냥   기분   좋으라고
Me Crisis Situation I tried to help Even if the dog was alive I gave it to you Just Feel good
I gave it to the dog even if it was alive to help me in a crisis situation, but I just wanted it to feel good
있는   이벤트
there event
event in
왜   왜   왜   왜   왜   왜도망가는데   갑자기
Why Why Why Why Why Why are you running away Suddenly
Why why why why why why why are you running away all of a sudden
갑자기   도망가라고   하는데   아잠깐만   넘어   어   당황스러워서   지금
Suddenly   they say to run away   wait a minute   go over it   uh   I'm embarrassed   now
Suddenly they tell me to run away
어디로   도망가야   될지   모르겠어요   지금어   잘   도망갔나요
Where   should I run away  I don't know if it will be   now   well   did you run away?
I don't know where to run, did you run away well now?
잘   도망간   건가오케이
Well   ran away   Geongaok
Did you run away okay?
빠져나갈   방법은   없다고비밀번호   5913
There is no   way to escape. Password  5913
There is no way out, password 5913
달려   달려   달려
run   run   run
run run run
어   뭐야   나온   거   아니야이거   바깥이잖아
Uh   what is this   that came out   no this is   it's outside
Uh, what's that? It's outside.
이상한
weird
지형이야   이제   거리도   나왔으니   마을을벗어날   방법을   찾아보자
It's terrain  Now that   the streets  are out, let's find a way  to get out of town
It's the terrain, now that the streets are out, let's find a way to get out of town.
지하로   가자여기   아닌   거   같네
Let's go to the basement Here It's not like
Let's go underground. I don't think it's here.
여긴   지옥   같은데
This place seems like   hell
It looks like hell
여기네
here it is
여기가   왔네오케이   제발
Here it is   you are here ok  please
here you come ok please
여기로   들어가면   아까   거기로들어가지는   건가
If you go   here,   will you go there   before?
If you go in here, will you go in there?
아니   근데   여기   분위기   이상하다니까
No   but   here   the atmosphere   is weird
No, but the atmosphere here is strange.
분위기   왜   이래   여기
Atmosphere   why   like this   here
What's the atmosphere like here
나   뭔가   잘못   들어온   거   같아애초에   여기   오는게   아니었어
I  something wrong I think I came in in the first place here wasn't coming
I think something went wrong, I wasn't here in the first place
전화   소리   뭐야
Call Sound What is it?
what's the phone call
저기   안에   전화
Over there   inside   phone
call in there
전화기   써서   구조   요청해야   돼
Phone Use Rescue You have to request
I need to call for help on the phone
이건   뭐지출구가   여기   있네
This is   what is the exit   here
What is this? The exit is here
하지만   샀을   끈을   무언가를   찾아야   해볼트   커터
But   I bought   string   I need to find   something   bolt   cutter
But I need to find something for the string I bought, the bolt cutter
적이   뭔가   있는데   돈이   없어레버   같은게   있는데   자판기에
There is an enemy something  There is no money Lever There is something  At the vending machine
I have an enemy, but I don't have money.
손전등   어디   간   거야   그   어겨우
Flashlight Where  went  it's  that
Where did the flashlight go?
어제무슨   상황이야   갑자기   왜
What was yesterday   situation   suddenly   why
What happened yesterday, why suddenly
뭐야나   손전등   갑자기   지워졌는데
What is it  Flashlight Suddenly It got erased
What is it, the flashlight suddenly disappeared
여기   들어가라는   건가
is this saying   to enter?
Do you want to come in here?
무서워
scared
돈   찾아야   되는   걸까   돈
Money   I have to find it   I wonder if it is
Should I find money? Money
죽지
die
엘리베이터가   작동하지   않습니다발전기에   연료가   떨어지고   시동   레버가
The elevator  does not work  the generator is out of   fuel  and the starter   lever is
Elevator does not workThe generator is running out of fuel and the start lever is
고장   났네요연료를   찾아야   될까   레버는   아까
It's out of order I have to find fuel .
It's broken. Should I look for fuel? The lever was earlier.
자판기   있었고
There was a vending machine
there was a vending machine
이거다
this is it
레버에   휘발유레몬   아까   봤죠
On the lever gasoline lemon  I saw it earlier
Gasoline lemon on the lever. I saw it before.
휘발유[음악]
petrol [music]
방금도   손에
Just now   in your hand
just in hand
[음악]
[music]
아   밖에   나오니까
Ah   because it comes out
oh i'm coming out
[음악]밀폐된   공간이   아니어서
[Music] It's not an enclosed   space
[Music] It's not an enclosed space
아   뭐   이거   가뿐하네요   이제
Ah   what   this   is so easy   now
Oh well, this is easy now
[음악]별거   없구만
[Music] Nothing special
[음악]
[music]
보여줄게   있어   시소   옆   바위   밑을확인해   봐
I'll show you   I have it   seesaw   next to   rock   check under it   look
I have something to show you, check under the rock next to the seesaw
[음악]시소   옆에
[Music] Next to the seesaw
[MUSIC] Next to the seesaw
[음악]
[music]
다여기야
It's all here
이건가   바위[음악]
This is  rock [music]
This Is Rock [Music]
하하하   이제   빨간   냉장고로   이동해
Hahaha now red go to the refrigerator
Hahaha Now go to the red refrigerator
나랑   장난치는   건가
Are you playing   with me?
are you kidding me
[음악]아까   그   냉장고인데
[Music] Before That It's a refrigerator
[Music] It's that refrigerator.
냉장고가   움직인다
The refrigerator   moves
refrigerator is moving
연다[음악]
open [music]
마당에   있는   분홍색   천   봤어   그   뒤에뭐가   있는지   궁금하지   않아   마당에
in the yard Pink cloth I saw what  is behind it I wonder I don't know in the yard
I saw the pink cloth in the yard. I don't know what's behind it. In the yard
있는   분홍색   천[음악]
there pink cloth [music]
pink cloth [music]
어마이가   너무   많이   갓   너무   많이   갓
My gosh   so   a lot   god   so   a lot   god
Mom too much god too much god
도였지
was also
아니   이제   할머니가   아닌가
No now isn’t it the grandmother
no, she's not a grandma anymore
주민들   미쳤나   봐[음악]
Residents Crazy Look [Music]
Residents must be crazy [Music]
빨리   뭔가분홍색   천   마당에
Hurry up something pink cloth in the yard
something soon on the pink cloth yard
그게   어느   쪽에   있을까잠깐만   여기
Which side  is it on? Wait a minute  here
Which side is it on? Wait here
만   한번   딱   훑어보고더   이상   오지   말자
Only   once   just   look through   more than   don't come
Let's just take a look and don't come again
설마   이건가[음악]
No way   this [music]
Could this be [Music]
어   뭐야
uh   what
uh what
여기는
here is
무슨   아지트   같아
What   hideout  is like
what a hideout
내   아지트가   아름답지   않나요   저는우리   가족과   마을   전체   일어나기
My  hideout isn't it beautiful isn't it my family and  town whole wake up
Isn't my hideout beautiful? I wake up my family and the whole village
시작한   모든   참혹한   일들을   피해이곳에   숨어   지냈는데   이제는   오히려
I started  all the   cruel   things  I was hiding   in this place   but now
I've been hiding in this place, avoiding all the terrible things that started, but now
구룡에   살아있는   사람이   없어서다행이라고   생각해요   그   동전에   필요할
I think it's a relief that   there are no   people   living in Kowloon.
I'm glad there's no one alive in Kowloon. I need that coin.
겁니다[음악]
I'm gonna [music]
동전
coin
감사합니다
thank you
고맙습니다[음악]
thank you [music]
자판기   가서이제
Vending machine   go now
Go to the vending machine now
동전을   써주면   돼
If you write a coin  , it's okay
You can write a coin
여기는   뭐   하면   될까연결된   곳인가
Is this a   place that connects to   if I do  ?
What can I do here? Is this a connected place?
[음악]어   전화기
[MUSIC] Uh phone
지금은   안   되네
not   now
not now
여기   기름   같은   거   없으려나   휘발유
Here oil there is no  thing gasoline
There's no such thing as oil here. Gasoline.
[음악]
[music]
방금   사람   지나갔어
people  just passed by
Someone just passed by
자판기
vending machine
자판기에   가서[음악]
Go   to the vending machine [music]
Go to the vending machine [music]
자판기에   가서
Go   to the vending machine
go to vending machine
자판기에   가서[음악]
Go   to the vending machine [music]
Go to the vending machine [music]
레버를꺼내주고
take out the lever
그   다음이제
That   then now
then now
[음악]휘발유를   찾아서
[MUSIC] Finding Gas
[Music] Finding Gasoline
저   앞에   사람   있네가까이   가면   갑툭튀   나온다   아까처럼
That   there is a   person in front of you   close to you   and you go   out of nowhere   will come out   just like before
There's a person in front of me. If you go closer, it pops out like before.
비명   지르면서   달려올지도   몰라   절대안   올라
While screaming  may come running I don't know absolutely not go up
They might come running screaming, they'll never climb
자   마음의   준비
Now   heart   preparation
prepare your heart
아
ah
[음악]세요   그냥
[Music] Seriously just
[Music] Say just
괜찮아
are you okay
일단   레버아   나   뒤보기   진짜   싫다   제발
First of all  Lever Me Looking back Really I hate it Please
First of all, Lever, I really hate looking back, please
[음악]
[music]
왜   왜이런   소리가   나오는   거야   배경음이
Why  why is this   the sound   coming out   the background sound
Why is this sound coming out? The background sound
여기에
Here
상황이   좋지   않아요   내   딸이가출했는데   뭐가   문제인지   모르겠어요
The situation is  not good not  my my daughter ran away from home what  is the problem I don't know
Things are bad. My daughter ran away and I don't know what's wrong.
아내는   사흘   동안   욕조에서   나오지않고   있고   주변   사람들   모두   미쳤어요
My wife   for three days    did not come out of the bathtub  and   the people around her   everyone   went crazy
My wife hasn't gotten out of the bathtub for three days and everyone around me is crazy.
어떻게   해야   할까요   전에는   눈치채지못했는데   대관에서   가스가   나옵니다
What should I do   I didn't notice  before, but  Gas comes out of  .
What should I do? I didn't notice it before, but gas is coming out of the gauze.
전부   그   사람   때문인   것   같아요도와주세요
It's all   that   person   I think it's   please help
I think it's all because of him please help
자   100원에서   가스가   나온다   그랬어언제든지   갑툭튀가   튀어나올   수   있어
Now From 100 won Gas comes out That's right  A sudden burst  It can come out
Now, gas comes out of 100 won. It can pop out at any time.
가스   소리
gas   sound
gas sound
괜찮아   그들은이동네에서   우리를   쫓아내려고   합니다
It's okay They're trying to kick us  out of the neighborhood
It's ok they're trying to kick us out of town
정부는   우리가   여기서   죽어가고   있다는사실을   숨기고   있습니다
The government   is hiding  the fact that we are   here   dying .
The government is hiding the fact that we are dying here
여기   휘발유통에   있어
It's here  at the gas tank
here in the gas tank
[음악]
[music]
[음악]자
[music] Now
갑툭튀   조심
Suddenly   be careful
be careful
[음악]
[music]
안   무섭네
An  that's scary
I'm not afraid
하나도   안   무서워
Not at all  I'm scared
I'm not scared at all
요레버를
lever
기름   넣고레버
Oil   put lever
Add oil lever
온
on
엘리베이터   작동   가능해요
Elevator  works  is possible
Elevator can work
[음악]
[music]
아   뭐야
ah  what
ah what
한번   나왔으니까   당분간   또   안나오겠지
Once   came out   for the time being   again   won't come out
Once I came out, I won't come back for a while.
엘리베이터   개같이   무섭게   생겼네
Elevator  looks like a dog  scary
He looks like an elevator dog
엘리베이터에서   멀리   떨어져   있잖아
From the elevator far away  you know
You're far from the elevator
[음악]
[music]
내가   꿈을   꾸고   있는   걸까
Am I   dreaming   or am I
am i dreaming
뭐   하는   장소야[음악]
What  is the   place [Music]
What are you doing [music]
볼트   커터
bolt   cutter
bolt cutter
드디어월드컵도
Finally the World Cup
이렇게   평온할   리가   없는데뭐지이   분위기
Like this   calm   Lee   what is this   atmosphere
There's no way I could be this calm. What is this atmosphere?
[음악]갑니다
[music] I'm going
문   닫힐   때   뭐   나오려고절단으로   할   거야
When the door   is closed  what  will   do   by cutting to come out
When the door closes, I'm going to cut it to get out
[음악]
[music]
자   이제   볼트   커터   쓰기만   하면   돼자   다   왔어
Now now bolt cutter Just write  and you can do it   everything  is here
Now all you have to do is use the bolt cutters.
괜찮아나가기만   하면   돼   어려운   거   없어   뭐
It's okay, just get out  and it's okay It's difficult There's no   what
It's okay, you just have to move on, there's nothing difficult
나와도   괜찮아   저기   게임이야어차피   게임이야
Even with me   It's okay   over there   it's a game anyway   it's a game
It's okay if I come out, over there, it's a game, it's a game anyway
[음악]
[music]
너   설마[음악]
You   No way [Music]
You can't [music]
은혜가   부러운   거니내   뒤를   잘   봐줘야   돼
Eunhye I'm envious Gunnie You should look after me  well
Are you envious of Eun-hye? You have to take good care of me
나   너한테살아   준   거   기억하지
I I live for you Jun Geo I remember
I remember giving you life
어[음악]
uh [music]
쳐다보지   마   무서우니까
Don't look at me  because I'm scared
Don't look at me because I'm scared
드디어   나온   건가
Is it finally   out
did it finally come out
장난   아니고
joking   no
no kidding
여보   뭐   마을   주민들이야   뭐야   왜이래
Honey What The village Residents What What are you doing?
Honey, what are the villagers, what are you doing?
여기   이상해
It's weird here
it's weird here
내가   너무   아까
I   so   not too long ago
i was too soon
[음악]나가야   돼
[Music] Gotta go   Yes
[MUSIC] I gotta get out
[음악]가스에   영향을   받아서   이렇게   된   걸까
[Music] Was it   affected by the gas ?
[Music] Did it happen because of the gas?
주민들
residents
어드디어
where
아   드디어드디어   나왔어   집에   갈   수   있다
Ah   finally   I came out   I can go   home   I can
Ah, finally, I'm finally out, I can go home
와야   간만에   진짜   어
Come on   long time no see   really   uh
It's been a while, really
퀄리티   미쳤다   분위기
Quality Crazy Atmosphere
quality crazy atmosphere
어마어마하구먼가성비   최고네   7,800원에이   정도
Incredible cost performance   best   7,800 won   about
It's amazing, it's the best value for money. It's about 7,800 won.
퀄리티는
quality is
[음악]
[music]
뭐야아직   끝나지   않은   건가   최근   구룡에
What is it yet   not over   not   is it   recently   in Kowloon
What's not over yet? Recently in Kowloon
다녀온   사람들로부터   경찰   신고가   많이들어오고   있는데요   이들은   실존하지
There are a lot of   police   reports from   people who have been there  , but they are   real.
There are a lot of police reports coming in from people who have been there, but they don't exist.
않는   도시를   봤다고   주장합니다5년   전에   철거된   구룡   성벽   도시는
claims to have seen a  city that does not exist that was demolished 5 years  ago
Claims to have seen a city that does not
중국   최악의   도시   중   하나였습니다철거   직전에는   이곳에서   범죄와
China was one of the worst cities demolition just before  in this place crime and
It was one of China's worst cities. Prior to demolition, it was home to crime and
불미스러운   살인   사건이   급증하기도했죠   사람들은   정부가   구룡을   철거하기
Unsavory  murder  incidents  also increased  people  government Kowloon demolished
There has also been a spike in unsavory murders. People say that the government wants to demolish Kowloon.
위해   참혹한   수단을   동원했다고   믿고있습니다
I believe that   cruel   means   were mobilized for
I believe he used cruel means to
근데   마지막까지   왜   그러세요
But   until the end   why   do you do that
But why are you like that until the end?
어이거   누르면   또   뭐   나오는   거   아니야
Oops Press it  Again What comes out That's not
If you press this, nothing else comes out
잘   만들었다
Well done
well made
진짜   퀄리티도   좋았고분위기도   좋았고
Really   the quality   was good and the atmosphere was also   good
The quality was really good and the atmosphere was good.
웰컴투코울은   구령에   오신   것을   환영합니다
Welcome to Coul
Welcome to Cole welcomes you to Guryung
여기서   마무리할게요   좋아요
I'll finish here   I like it
I'll finish here. Okay
[음악]
[music]
그래   아   너무   쉬워
Yes   ah   it's so   easy
yes ah so easy